{
    {
        question : "Singrauli can be best categorised as",
        option : [
            "mining town",
            "garrison town",
            "educational town",
            "religious town"
        ],
        correct : "mining town"
    },
    {
        question : "rain gardens are primarily meant to",
        option : [
            "reduce water usage",
            "increase recharge to groundwater",
            "protect existing water sources",
            "increase water flow to streams"
        ],
        correct : "increase recharge to groundwater"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is/ are example(s) of mitigation measures to mitigate impacts of linear infrastructure on wildlife?",
        option : [
            "land bridges",
            "canopy bridges",
            "glider poles",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "Varanasi can be best categorised as",
        option : [
            "mining town",
            "garrison town",
            "educational town",
            "religious town"
        ],
        correct : "religious town"
    },
    {
        question : "'the ability to produce a good using fewer inputs than another place' is",
        option : [
            "comparative advantage",
            "absolute advantage",
            "production advantage",
            "resource advantage"
        ],
        correct : "absolute advantage"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is a factor governing barrier effect of roads?",
        option : [
            "presence and location of animal crossings",
            "movement pattern of species",
            "species specific preference of road use",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "Visakhapatnam can be best categorised as",
        option : [
            "administrative town",
            "industrial town",
            "transport town",
            "commercial town"
        ],
        correct : "transport town"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is a factor governing barrier effect of roads?",
        option : [
            "traffic intensity",
            "speed of vehicles",
            "driver sensitivity",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is/ are example(s) of mitigation measures to mitigate impacts of linear infrastructure on wildlife?",
        option : [
            "bridge underpass",
            "box culverts",
            "pipe culverts",
            "all of these"
        ],
        correct : "all of these"
    },
    {
        question : "Bhilai can be best categorised as ",
        option : [
            "administrative town",
            "industrial town",
            "transport town",
            "commercial town"
        ],
        correct : "industrial town"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these is not a use value?",
        option : [
            "direct value",
            "indirect value",
            "option value",
            "existence value"
        ],
        correct : "existence value"
    },
    {
        question : "'the conditions determined by physical, social, economic and environmental factors or processes which increase the susceptibility of an individual, a community, assets or systems to the impact of hazards.' is a definition for",
        option : [
            "hazard",
            "exposure",
            "vulnerability",
            "disaster"
        ],
        correct : "vulnerability"
    },
    {
        question : "'a process, phenomenon or human activity that may cause loss of life, injury or other health impacts, property damage, social and economic disruption or environmental degradation.' is a definition for ",
        option : [
            "hazard",
            "exposure",
            "vulnerability",
            "disaster"
        ],
        correct : "hazard"
    },
    {
        question : "which of these uses imputed willingness to pay?",
        option : [
            "market price method",
            "replacement cost method",
            "travel cost method",
            "contingent valuation method"
        ],
        correct : "replacement cost method"
    },
    {
        question : "'a serious disruption of the functioning of a community or a society at any scale due to hazardous events interacting with conditions of exposure, vulnerability and capacity, leading to one or more of the following: human, material, economic and environmental losses and impacts' is a definition for",
        option : [
            "hazard",
            "exposure",
            "vulnerability",
            "disaster"
        ],
        correct : "disaster"
    }
}
